#### Contact

(310) 658-2303 (Mobile)

azmiamir@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amir-azmi-96079a1b (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Team Leadership Project Planning

**Customer Satisfaction** 

## Languages

French English

Arabic

#### Certifications

CompTIA A+

# **Amir Azmi**

Direct Sales Agent at Charter Spectrum El Segundo

## Summary

I have over ten years of experience in small and big office Windows and Apple desktop support, printer support, and networking.

Logical reasoning, creative problem-solving skills, and efficient time management. With the capacity to work independently as well as in a team-driven environment.

## Experience

### **Charter Spectrum**

Direct Sales Agent February 2021 – November 2021 (8 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

- Planning, implementing and managing individual marketing and sales plans for Greater Los Angeles Area.
- Utilized human relations, communication, and negotiation skills to market and sell home security systems, home internet, home television, and home telephone services.
- Responsible for identifying client needs while researching ways to improve the quality of their services.
- Effective at finding cost-saving options for new customers, often reducing their costs by as much as 50%.
- Met and most often exceeded monthly sales goals by 20 50%.
- Install and activate all Spectrum hardware equipment. (Modem & Router)
- Connect all wireless appliances devices to the new wireless network.

#### PCW Tech Group

Information Technology Specialist July 2017 - March 2020 (2 years 9 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

- Responsible for managing, coaching, and driving the performance of the Customer Service team to achieve KPIs.
- Been a point of escalation for all customer service issues.
- Ensured consistently high levels of customer excellence at all times.
- Managed to help desk support and resolved problems to ensure enduser satisfaction.
- Provided superior customer service, customer satisfaction.
- Walk end-users through a variety of problem-solving processes.
- · Provided necessary training to computer users.
- Assessed hardware and software usage, network, and device connectivity.

- Managed VoIP phone systems, including deploying and supporting phones and extensions.
- Resolved technical problems with Local Area Networks (LAN), phone systems, virtual environments.
- Acted as a point of contact to set up PCs and deploy new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.
- Modify configurations, utilities, software default settings for the local workstation.
- Build and install new workstations, peripheral equipment, software, and migrate data as part of the upgrade process.
- Ensured each workstation had the necessary equipment needed and any additional specialized equipment to support productivity.
- Maintained an inventory of supplies and spare parts, OEMlicensing management.
- Configured and managed user accounts on Active Directory.
- Set up smart conference rooms for meetings, ensuring internet connectivity, and mirroring laptops to the TV for presentations.
- Secured building access controls and observing the uptime of the CCTV system.

Information Technology Specialist Feb 2015 - Jun 2017 (2 years 5 months) Cairo Governorate, Egypt

- Developed strong links to internal and external stakeholders.
- Promoted a hardworking, successful, and pleasant team environment.
- Motivated customers to use the company's services more.
- IT-related work involves provisioning and maintaining internal systems, as well as building tools for the automation of routine tasks.
- Administered mobile device management systems.
- Administered provisioning of new internal hardware and user setup.
- Implemented and maintained an IT asset management system.
- Implemented and monitored security measures for the protection of computer systems, networks, and information.
- Educated users success team on routine problems to allow them to resolve things directly.
- Assisted users with IT-related issues on-site or remotely.

#### United Nations OCHA

ICT Associate

Apr 2012 - Jan 2015 (2 years 10 months) Cairo Governorate, Egypt

- Administrated under VMware server (ISA firewall server, Domain server, Data server, WEB servers, FTP server).
- Administrated Lotus Note and Black-Berry service server.
- Administrated the Avaya VOIP server.
- Designed and established a backup strategy for all virtual servers and data.
- Implemented and managed PC setup and deployment for new employees using standard hardware, images, and software.

- Responsible for handling and purchasing IT types of equipment.
- Managed ICT inventory in coordination with the administration unit.
- Provide technical support for specific Satellite internet VSAT, GPS, Thuraya phones.

#### **Vodafone International Services**

Account Advisor June 2009 - March 2012 (2 years 10 months) Giza Governorate, Egypt

#### Account advisor-Team leader:

- Served UK customers in England.
- Set and maintained standards of excellence and professionalism.
- Applied excellent call control to resolve escalated calls successfully.
- Provided customer service support and was their primary escalation point for all customer service.
- Diagnosed and Troubleshoot to solve problems due to Vodafone product issues.
- Log customer complaints and find solutions within determined time frames; list suggestions made and analyzed for validity and possible implementation and resolution.
- Reviewed and analyzed historical account information as needed.
- Corrected transaction mistakes when debits and credits do not balance.
- Resolved problems or discrepancies concerning customers' accounts.
- Assisted with training new hire employees and showing them how to navigate through systems and programs that advisors use daily.
- Developed and coached customer service agents by reviewing recorded calls and providing feedback.
- Assisted customers with questions and concerns about why their bill increased, billing cycles, due dates, extensions, etc.

#### ELNG (Egyptian Liquefied Natural Gas)

IT Support Specialist

2008 - 2009 (1 year)

Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

Responsible for maintaining and support the following items for entire LNG staff in IDKU site:

- Troubleshoot entire LNG user's software, hardware, and IP phone set conflicts and problems.
- Supported the Windows operating system, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Exchange, Active Directory, PDA interfaces, etc.
- Troubleshoot MFP printers, copiers, digital sender, and faxes problems.
- · Maintained and monitor the network.
- Configured and managed ELNG user's connectivity on Cisco IP telephone.
- Participated in the server's room transfer project.
- Part of the team responsible for implementing the wireless access points plan.

#### X-Lab Group

IT Support Senior Eng. network administrator August 2006 - February 2008 (1 year 7 months) Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Support Senior Eng. network admin of the Technical Department. Handling all main project & technical team projects have done:

- The Sharm el-Sheikh International Arbitration Center (shiac.com)
- · network infra cabled and wireless.
- · Internet leased line connection with the server firewall.
- · Ip-sec webcam.
- Audio and video conference system.
- Smartboard system.
- Kabo JIL factory installed and managed database for 46 fingerprint devices.
- IT Support for Lycee Francais Alexandria school (part of the French consul) Maintenance contract.

#### **PC LINK**

IT Site Maintenance Eng. January 2005 - August 2006 (1 year 8 months) Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Site Maintenance Eng. for Alexandria Carbon Black Co. Handling more than 150 PC's, Printers, Copier (hardware & software) Troubleshooting, maintenance, and networking.

#### New PC Planet

IT Support

March 1997 - December 2001 (4 years 10 months) Alexandria Governorate, Egypt

IT Supervisor in the Technical Support Department.

- Excellent experience in networking.
- Computer assembly.
- Installation of Windows and other common software.
- Troubleshooting most hardware and software problems & hardware conflicts.
- Resolving driver installation problems.
- System admin for the Center for French Studies (CEA) network consisting of 30 PC's and internet leased line.

## Education

#### Special Studies Academy

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering, Quality control and quality assurance for mechanical products. (1999 - 2003)

College St. Marc, Alexandria

High school degree, Collège Saint Marc · (1983 - 1999)